A Guide to Warren Chappell Illustrations 1983-1985
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Warren Chappell Illustrations 1983-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10204-ac
16 items
The collection consists of Chappell's original art work and related material, 1983-1985, for American Masterworks Library.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Mr. Warren Chappell of Charlottesville, Virginia, gave his artwork to the Library on July 20, 1987.
Scope and Content Information
This collection of original artwork by Warren Chappell, ca. 1983-1985, and undated, consists of ten pen and ink sketches and six setting-copy glossy prints of eight American literary figures, and two designs, a spread eagle logo and a quill pen and star. Chappell prepared the drawings of the American authors to illustrate a series of American literary classics.
Contents List
- Louisa May Alcott 1984
- Stephen Crane 1984
- Nathaniel Hawthorne 1985
- Jack London n.d.
- Herman Melville n.d.
- Edgar Allan Poe 1984
- Henry David Thoreau 1984
- Mark Twain 1984
- Quill Pen and Star Design 1983
- Spread Eagle Logo Design n.d.